## Sebastien VARRETTE, PhD

# Research Associate, Doctor in Computer Science,

specialized in Distributed Platforms Security and HPC systems.

Phone: +33(0)6 74 57 90 05 E-mail: Sebastien.Varrette@uni.lu Home page: http://varrette.gforge.uni.lu

Born on November 27th, 1979 (in France) Married (2004), two children (2007,2010)

ENGINEER EXPERTISE: High Performance Computing (HPC), Grid & Cluster Platforms.

I'm administrating cluster-based HPC systems since 2003 (Linux environment)

Keywords: HPC, Debian, Xen, Puppet, OpenLDAP, git

MAIN RESEARCH DOMAINS: Security and Evaluation of Distributed Computing Platforms (clusters, grids or clouds).

Relevant contributions in which I'm involved:

- $\bullet$  Code Obfuscation  $% \left( 1\right) =\left( 1\right$
- Crash/cheating faults analysis in grid platforms
- Performance evaluation & Energy efficiency of HPC/Cloud platforms
- Design of the authentication system of Grid5000
  Developing security awareness by education

### Education

| 2007 | Ph.D. in Computer Science,   | with honours (Excellent/Outstanding) |  |
|------|--|--------------------------------------|--|
|      | University of Luxembourg (UL) & Institut National Polytechnique de Grenoble (INPG) |                                      |  |
| 2003 | M.Sc. in Computer Science  | with honours (TB/First Class)        |  |
|      | Speciality: Cryptology, Security and Information Codin                             | ng (CSCI), rank: 1st                 |  |
| 2003 | Master's Degree in Engineering (Telecoms ENSI)                                     | MAG) with honours $(B/2.1)$          |  |
|      | Speciality: Computer Sciences and Telecommunications                               | rank: top $10\%$                     |  |

## **Employment**

| 2011 - now  | Research Associate (UL, Luxembourg)              |
|-------------|--|
| 2007 - 2010 | Scientific collaborator (ul, Luxembourg)         |
| 2004 - 2007 | Research Assistant (UL, Luxembourg)              |
| 2003        | System administrator (ID-IMAG, Grenoble, France) |

#### **Publications**

| Publication category                                       | Quantity |
|--|----------|
| PhD Thesis   | 1        |
| Books  | 3        |
| Magazine   | 1        |
| Book Chapters  | 7        |
| International journals                                     | 4        |
| International conferences with proceedings and reviews     | 26       |
| (French) national conferences with proceedings and reviews | 4        |
| International conferences with proceedings                 | 1        |
| International conferences with reviews                     | 6        |
| Masters Thesis   | 1        |
| Technical Reports  | 8        |
| Miscellaneous  | 1        |
| Total:   | 63       |

|          |                       | Citations:149,Years:11    |                     |                      |                               |
|----------|-----------------------|---------------------------|---------------------|----------------------|-------------------------------|
| or Peris | h   Cites/year: 13.55 | Cites/paper: $3.10/2.0/0$ | Cites/author: 58.98 | Papers/author: 20.25 | Query date: <b>2013-05-20</b> |